# NARENDRA RAWAT

narendra.rawat620@gmail.com

8826333960

**Q** Delhi, India 110096

https://www.linkedin.com/in/narendra-rawat-25a7959a/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Persistent professional equipped with over 8 years of comprehensive experience in Software Development industry. Provides strong technical direction across multiple projects. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions and global project management.

### **SKILLS**

- Java
- · Web application development
- Git
- JavaScript
- MongoDB
- RESTful API
- Kubernetes
- · Advanced Data Structures
- System improvements
- · Microservices Architecture

### **EDUCATION**

University of Delhi PGDAV College • 06/2014

**Bachelor of Science:** Computer Science

Anglo Sanskrit Senior Secondary School

Delhi • 06/2010

High School Diploma

### **WORK HISTORY**

Noduco Software Solutions - Senior Software Engineer Noida, India • 11/2021 - Current

- Implemented the RESTful APIs using Spring Boot along with Mockito for unit testing
- Working in micro-services architecture using spring boot and mongoDB
- Contributed to the system design and development of microservices by actively participating in the creation of the overall system architecture, ensuring scalability, flexibility, and adherence to industry best practices
- Implemented monitoring tools for application endpoints to analyze using Prometheus and Grafana
- Fixed & troubleshot technical issues developers during the project lifecycle
- Resolved application based issues through debugging, market research, and investigation.

# Vitrana Pvt Ltd - Senior Software Engineer

Noida, India • 11/2016 - 11/2021

- Implemented the RESTful APIs using Spring Boot along with unit Testing
- · Continuous Integration using Jenkins and deployment on Tomcat
- Developed Email Scheduler service for email notifications using Aspose Mail application
- Coordinated with the Technical Architects to create high-level UI and detailed design for Java-based applications.
- Performed coding & testing in compliance with the approved life cycle methodologies
- Resolved application-based issues through debugging, market research, and investigation.
- Provide assistance for junior associates and performed code review.

# Times Internet - Junior Java Developer

Noida, India • 10/2015 - 10/2016

- Developed and maintained E-commerce application based on OPENTAPS framework, which followed MVC design pattern
- Defined the objectives & functionalities based on business

requirements.

- Developed RESTful web-services using Spring framework.
- End to end testing of the project for the user journey
- Developed detailed design documentation to recommend changes to the existing Java infrastructure
- Drafted & produced releases of software components and contributed in all phases of the development lifecycle

## **LANGUAGES**

English

Hindi

## **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

- Playing and Watching football
- Consuming technological content
- Listening to Music and Singing

## **HOBBIES**

- · Consuming technological content
- Watching & playing football
- Listening to music